{"data":{"site":{"pathPrefix":"/restaurant-inspections"},"postgres":{"establishment":[{"establishmentid":"5137","name":"Detroit Burger Bar","address":"3990 John R St","zipcode":"48201","owner":"John D. Murray/Olde Det.Burger","licenseNumber":"082992","licenseType":"Fixed Establishment","establishmentType":"Food Service Establishment","establishmentStatus":"Open","riskCategory":"High","reviewFrequencyDays":"180.0","coords":"-83.05697,42.35067","geojson":{"id":"5137","type":"Feature","geometry":{"type":"Point","coordinates":[-83.0569670039999,42.350668985]},"properties":{"name":"Detroit Burger Bar","owner":"John D. Murray/Olde Det.Burger","address":"3990 John R St","zipcode":"48201","license_type":"Fixed Establishment","risk_category":"High","license_number":"082992","establishmentid":"5137","establishment_type":"Food Service Establishment","establishment_status":"Open","review_frequency_days":"180.0","most_recent_license_date":"5/7/2018"}},"nearbyList":[{"establishmentid":"51622827","name":"Kit Chen Thai at DMC","address":"3990 John R St","zipcode":"48201"},{"establishmentid":"4994","name":"Harper Hutzel Hospital ","address":"3990 John R","zipcode":"48201"},{"establishmentid":"51622849","name":"Harpe-Hutzel Hospital","address":"3990 John R St","zipcode":"48201"},{"establishmentid":"5136","name":"Estia Greek Street Food","address":"3990 John R","zipcode":"48201"},{"establishmentid":"5135","name":"Chiqui Mexican","address":"3990 John R ","zipcode":"48201"},{"establishmentid":"51622634","name":"Chick-Fil-A","address":"3990 John R St","zipcode":"48201"},{"establishmentid":"3807","name":"Great Lakes Coffee Beanery","address":"3990 John R St","zipcode":"48201"},{"establishmentid":"51622839","name":"Dunkin Donuts OM DMC Donuts","address":"3990 John R St","zipcode":"48201"},{"establishmentid":"5198","name":"Bigalora Wood Fired Cucina","address":"3990 John R","zipcode":"48201"},{"establishmentid":"5142","name":"Menchie's Frozen Yogurt","address":"3990 John R St","zipcode":"48201"}],"inspectionsByEstablishmentidList":[{"inspectionid":"44620","inspectionDate":"2018-12-26T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[]},{"inspectionid":"42453","inspectionDate":"2018-06-04T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"3-501.16","violationDescription":"Except during preparation, cooking, or cooling, or when time is used as the public health control POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD) shall be maintained:\r\n(A)  135ºF or above, except that roasts properly cooked and cooled may be held              at a temperature of 130ºF; or (P)\r\n(B)   At 41ºF or less (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Cold food item(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored above 41 degrees F","subProblem":"","location":"COOKING AREA","subLocation":"Cooler (top loader)","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-06-04T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Discard"},{"violationCode":"6-301.11","violationDescription":"Each HANDWASHING SINK or group of 2 adjacent HANDWASHING SINKS shall be provided with a supply of hand cleaning liquid, powder, or bar soap. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Soap","subItem":"at handsink kitchen","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"Hand sink(s)","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-06-04T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide adequate supply of soap at all hand sinks."},{"violationCode":"6-501.14","violationDescription":"(A) Intake and exhaust air ducts shall be cleaned and filters changed so they are not a source of contamination by dust, dirt, and other materials. \r\n(B) If vented to the outside, ventilation systems may not create a public health HAZARD or nuisance or unLAWful discharge.\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Ventilation system","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not clean","subProblem":"","location":"COOKING AREA","subLocation":"VENTILATION","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Clean"},{"violationCode":"4-602.13","violationDescription":"NonFOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of EQUIPMENT shall be cleaned at a frequency necessary to preclude accumulation of soil residues.\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Nonfood contact surface(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"THROUGHOUT FACILITY","subLocation":"NON FOOD CONTACT SURFACES","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Clean."},{"violationCode":"3-307.11","violationDescription":"FOOD shall be protected from contamination that may result from a factor or source not specified under Subparts 3-301 - 3-306.\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Food","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not protected","subProblem":"From contamination","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2018-06-04T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Protect against contamination"},{"violationCode":"2-402.11","violationDescription":"FOOD EMPLOYEES shall wear hair restraints such as hats, hair coverings or nets, beard restraints, and clothing that covers body hair, that are designed and worn to effectively keep their hair from contacting exposed FOOD; clean EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, and LINENS; or unwrapped SINGLE-SERVICE or SINGLE-USE ARTICLES.","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Hair restraint","subItem":"hair/beard net","problemDescription":"Not worn on head/hair","subProblem":"","location":"COOKING AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Provide hat or hair net."},{"violationCode":"6-501.12","violationDescription":"(A) PHYSICAL FACILITIES shall be cleaned as often as necessary to keep them clean.\r\n(B) Except spill cleanup, cleaning shall be done during periods when the least amount of FOOD is exposed such as after closing. ","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Physical facilities/structures","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"THROUGHOUT FACILITY","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Clean."}]},{"inspectionid":"40845","inspectionDate":"2017-11-08T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"4-302.12","violationDescription":"(A) FOOD TEMPERATURE MEASURING DEVICES shall be provided and readily accessible for use in ensuring attainment and maintenance of FOOD temperatures as specified under Chapter 3. (Pf)   \r\n(B) A TEMPERATURE MEASURING DEVICE with a suitable small-diameter probe that is designed to measure the temperature of thin masses shall be provided and readily accessible to accurately measure the temperature in thin FOODS such as MEAT patties and FISH filets. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Food thermometer(s)","subItem":"probe","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-11-09T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide as required"}]},{"inspectionid":"38897","inspectionDate":"2017-05-18T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"No","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"2-301.14","violationDescription":"FOOD EMPLOYEES shall clean their hands and exposed portions of their arms as specified under § 2-301.12 immediately before engaging in FOOD preparation including working with exposed FOOD, clean EQUIPMENT and UTENSILS, and unwrapped SINGLE-SERVICE and SINGLE-USE ARTICLES (P) and:\r\n(A)     After touching bare human body parts other than clean hands and clean, exposed portions of arms; (P)\r\n(B)     After using the toilet room; (P)\r\n(C)     After caring for or handling SERVICE ANIMALS or aquatic animals as specified in ¶ 2-403.11(B); (P).\r\n(D)     Except as specified in ¶ 2-401.11(B), after coughing, sneezing, using a handkerchief or disposable tissue, using tobacco, eating, or drinking; (P)\r\n(E)     After handling soiled EQUIPMENT or UTENSILS; (P)\r\n(F)     During FOOD preparation, as often as necessary to remove soil and contamination and to prevent cross contamination when changing tasks; (P)\r\n(G)     When switching between working with raw FOOD and working with READY-TO-EAT FOOD; (P)\r\n(H)     Before donning gloves for working with FOOD; (P) and\r\n(I)      After engaging in other activities that contaminate the hands. (P)","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Employee(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Did not wash hands","subProblem":"before handling ready to eat foods","location":"COOKING AREA","subLocation":"Lack of HAND WASHING","corrected":"No","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Hands shall be washed with hot water and soap for at least 20 seconds after contamination."},{"violationCode":"3-501.16","violationDescription":"Except during preparation, cooking, or cooling, or when time is used as the public health control POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD) shall be maintained:\r\n(A)  135ºF or above, except that roasts properly cooked and cooled may be held              at a temperature of 130ºF; or (P)\r\n(B)   At 41ºF or less (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Cold food item(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored above 41 degrees F","subProblem":"","location":"COOKING AREA","subLocation":"Cooler (top loader)","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-05-18T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Discard"},{"violationCode":"4-302.12","violationDescription":"(A) FOOD TEMPERATURE MEASURING DEVICES shall be provided and readily accessible for use in ensuring attainment and maintenance of FOOD temperatures as specified under Chapter 3. (Pf)   \r\n(B) A TEMPERATURE MEASURING DEVICE with a suitable small-diameter probe that is designed to measure the temperature of thin masses shall be provided and readily accessible to accurately measure the temperature in thin FOODS such as MEAT patties and FISH filets. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Food thermometer(s)","subItem":"probe","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"","location":"FACILITY","subLocation":"Lack of Food thermometer(s)","corrected":"No","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Provide as required"},{"violationCode":"4-601.11","violationDescription":"(A) EQUIPMENT FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES and UTENSILS shall be clean to sight and touch. (Pf)\r\n(B) The FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of cooking EQUIPMENT and pans shall be kept free of encrusted grease deposits and other soil accumulations. \r\n(C) NonFOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of EQUIPMENT shall be kept free of an accumulation of dust, dirt, FOOD residue, and other debris. \r\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Food-contact surface(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"DISH ROOM","subLocation":"Food contact surfaces","corrected":"No","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Keep clean."},{"violationCode":"4-501.14","violationDescription":"A WAREWASHING machine; the compartments of sinks, basins, or  other receptacles used for washing and rinsing EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, or raw FOODS, or laundering wiping cloths; and drainboards or other EQUIPMENT used to substitute for drainboards shall be cleaned as required.\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Warewashing equipment","subItem":"dishmachine","problemDescription":"Not cleaned","subProblem":"At least every 24 hours","location":"DISH ROOM","subLocation":"Sink (3-compartment/basins)","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Clean as specified above."},{"violationCode":"3-305.11","violationDescription":"FOOD shall be protected from contamination by storing the FOOD:\r\n(1)     In a clean, dry location;\r\n(2)     Where it is not exposed to splash, dust, or other contamination; and\r\n(3)     At least 15 cm (6 inches) above the floor, unless otherwise approved.\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Food item(s) in storage","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Exposed to dust, splash, or other contaminates","subProblem":"","location":"DISH ROOM","subLocation":"Food Storage","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Store in manner that does not contaminate items"},{"violationCode":"MFL289.2129","violationDescription":"Sec. 2129. (1) All of the following food establishments shall employ a minimum of 1 managerial employee who is currently certified under a personnel certification program accredited by the American national standards institute, utilizing the conference for food protection standards:  (a) A food service establishment that is not any of the following:    (i) Operating under a temporary food service establishment license.  (ii) A vending machine location.     (b) An extended retail food establishment.  (c) Operated within a retail grocery.  (2) An individual certified under subsection (1) shall be recognized with full faith and credit by the state and all local units of government throughout the state.  (3) The department may promulgate rules to do all of the following:  (a) Develop requirements for retail food establishments to follow when employing certified food safety managers or personnel.  (b) Set a reasonable date for compliance with the requirements under subdivision (a) taking into consideration existing local personnel certification requirements.  (c) Establish certification fees necessary to implement, maintain, and track certified individuals directly or by contract. The department may annually adjust the schedule of fees to provide that the fee charged is sufficient to cover the cost of the certification tracking program.  (d) Implement and enforce the requirements described in subdivision (a).    (4) The certification program developed by the American national standards institute, as it exists on April 1, 2008 , is incorporated by reference. The department may adopt updates to the certification program accreditation standards in subsection (1) by rule.     (5) This section does not prohibit any local legislative body from implementing a food handler program, an employee health certification program, or a manager certification program, if it is not in conflict with this section.","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Person-in-charge","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Missing","subProblem":"","location":"PERSON IN CHARGE","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Provide."},{"violationCode":"4-903.11","violationDescription":"Cleaned EQUIPMENT and UTENSILS, laundered LINENS, and SINGLE-SERVICE and SINGLE-USE ARTICLES shall be stored in an approved manner and location.\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Clean equipment/utensil(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Exposed to dust, splash, or other contaminates","subProblem":"","location":"DISH ROOM","subLocation":"Equipment storage","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Store in manner that does not contaminate items"}]},{"inspectionid":"36961","inspectionDate":"2016-10-18T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"3-501.14","violationDescription":"(A)  Cooked POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  shall be cooled:\r\n         (1)  Within 2 hours, from 135ºF to 70ºF; and (P) \r\n         (2)  Within 4 hours, from 70ºF to 41ºF or less (P)\r\n(B)  POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  prepared from ingredients at ambient temperature shall be cooled within 4 hours to 41F or less. (P)\r\n(C)  POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  received in compliance with LAWS   allowing a temperature above 41ºF during shipment from the supplier shall be cooled within 4 hours to 41ºF or less. (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Cooked food(s) cooled","subItem":"","problemDescription":"From 135 degrees f to 70 degrees F for more than 2 hours","subProblem":"","location":"DISH ROOM","subLocation":"IMPROPER COOLING","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2016-10-18T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Utilize shallow pans, ice baths, agitation, or quick chilling to cool food items."},{"violationCode":"3-501.16","violationDescription":"Except during preparation, cooking, or cooling, or when time is used as the public health control POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD) shall be maintained:\r\n(A)  135ºF or above, except that roasts properly cooked and cooled may be held              at a temperature of 130ºF; or (P)\r\n(B)   At 41ºF or less (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Cold food item(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored above 41 degrees F","subProblem":"","location":"COOKING AREA","subLocation":"Cooler (prep)","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2016-10-18T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Discard"},{"violationCode":"4-601.11","violationDescription":"(A) EQUIPMENT FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES and UTENSILS shall be clean to sight and touch. (Pf)\r\n(B) The FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of cooking EQUIPMENT and pans shall be kept free of encrusted grease deposits and other soil accumulations. \r\n(C) NonFOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of EQUIPMENT shall be kept free of an accumulation of dust, dirt, FOOD residue, and other debris. \r\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Food-contact surface(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"DISH ROOM","subLocation":"Food contact surfaces","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2016-10-18T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Clean."},{"violationCode":"5-205.11","violationDescription":"(A) A HANDWASHING SINK shall be maintained so that it is accessible at all times for EMPLOYEE use and used for no other purpose. (Pf)\r\n(B)  An automatic handwashing facility shall be used in accordance with manufacturer's instructions. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Handwashing sink(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not easily accessible","subProblem":"Items stored In","location":"DISH ROOM","subLocation":"OBSTRUCTED Handsink","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2016-10-18T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Remove items from handsink.  Do not store items at handsink."},{"violationCode":"5-103.11","violationDescription":"(A) The water source and system shall be of sufficient capacity to meet the peak water demands of the FOOD ESTABLISHMENT. (Pf)\r\n(B) Hot water generation and distribution systems shall be sufficient to meet the peak hot water demands throughout the FOOD ESTABLISHMENT. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Hot water supply","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Insufficient to meet demands","subProblem":"","location":"SINKS","subLocation":"Lack of HOT WATER","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2016-10-31T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide sufficient supply if hot water such as a larger or additional hot water heater."},{"violationCode":"6-501.18","violationDescription":"PLUMBING FIXTURES such as HANDWASHING SINKS, toilets, and urinals shall be cleaned as often as necessary to keep them clean. \r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Handwashing facility","subItem":"back","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"COOKING AREA","subLocation":"Handsink","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2016-10-18T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Clean."},{"violationCode":"3-304.12","violationDescription":"During pauses in FOOD preparation or dispensing, UTENSILS shall be stored:\r\n(A) In the FOOD with their handles above the top of the FOOD and the container;\r\n(B) In FOOD that is not POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS with their handles above the      top of the FOOD within containers or EQUIPMENT that can be closed, such as      bins of sugar, flour, or cinnamon;\r\n(C) On a clean portion of the FOOD preparation table or cooking EQUIPMENT\r\n(D)  In running water, such as dipper well.\r\n(E)  In a clean, protected location if the UTENSILS, such as ice scoops, are   used only with a FOOD that is not POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS; or\r\n(F)  In a container of water maintained at a temperature of at least 135° F.\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Dispensing utensil(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Improperly stored","subProblem":"To prevent contamination of food or food related items","location":"COOKING AREA","subLocation":"Food contact surfaces","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2016-10-18T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Store in manner that does not contaminate items"},{"violationCode":"4-501.11","violationDescription":"EQUIPMENT shall be maintained in a state of repair and condition that meets the requirements of the code.\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Equipment","subItem":"","problemDescription":"In poor repair","subProblem":"","location":"COOKING AREA","subLocation":"Cooler (prep)","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2016-10-31T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"4-501.14","violationDescription":"A WAREWASHING machine; the compartments of sinks, basins, or  other receptacles used for washing and rinsing EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, or raw FOODS, or laundering wiping cloths; and drainboards or other EQUIPMENT used to substitute for drainboards shall be cleaned as required.\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Warewashing equipment","subItem":"three compartment sink basins","problemDescription":"Not cleaned","subProblem":"","location":"DISH ROOM","subLocation":"Three compartment sink","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2016-10-18T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Clean as required above."}]}]}]}},"pageContext":{"eid":"5137"}}